Guide to the Roger W. Moss Collection of Manuscript, Original Art and Printed Material by and about Richard Shirley Smith
Yale Center for British Art, Rare Books and Manuscripts
- Correspondence, Series VI
  - Email to Simon Lawrence, 2009 July 2; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; 3 pages; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 75)
    Electronic mail; Lawrence, Simon, 1958-; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; Fleece Press
  - Email correspondence between Roger W. Moss and Simon Lawrence, 2009 July 3; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; 1 page; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 76)
    Moss and Lawrence discuss doing a limited private press run of a bibliography of Richard Shirley Smith's work.
    Electronic mail; Lawrence, Simon, 1958-; Moss, Roger W., 1940-
  - Email correspondence between Roger W. Moss and Richard Shirley Smith, 2009 July 17; Shirley Smith, Richard; 2 pages; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 77)
    Moss and Shirley Smith discuss the possibility of Iain Bain designing the Richard Shirley Smith bibliography.
    Electronic mail; Shirley Smith, Richard; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; Bain, Iain
  - Correspondence between Richard Shirley Smith and Roger W. Moss, 2009 July 27; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; 6 pages; 29.5 x 21.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 78)
    Moss and Shirley Smith discusses the Gruffyground Press Bibliography and Shirley Smith's designs for the Novello & Company scores. Moss encloses an email to Victoria Small regarding the Novello & Company scores, a Wikipedia entry on Novello & Company, and a photocopy of the engraving that appears on the cover of Moss Collection checklist.
    Correspondence; Shirley Smith, Richard; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; Gruffyground Press; Novello & Co.
  - Email to Richard Shirley Smith, 2009 August 8; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; 2 pages; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 79)
    Moss discusses the addition of two new items to the Richard Shirley Smith checklist, David Esslemont's Sixteen Contemporary Wood Engravers and the Folio Society edition of Jerome Carcopino's Daily Life in Ancient Rome.
    Electronic mail; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; Shirley Smith, Richard; Esslemont, David; Carcopino, Jérôme, 1881-1970
  - Email correspondence between Roger Moss and John Breckenridge of Mclean Books, 2009 August 13; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; 2 pages; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 80)
    Moss confirms the arrival of David Esslemont's Sixteen Contemporary Wood Engravers.
    Electronic mail; Breckenridge, John; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; Esslemont, David
  - Letter to Roger W. Moss, 2009 August 30; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 page; 29.5 x 21 cm (Box 2, Folder 81)
    Shirley Smith lists the engravings included in a recent shipment to Moss.
  - Letter to Roger W. Moss, 2009 September 12; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 page; 13 x 18 cm (Box 2, Folder 82)
    Shirley Smith discusses his box of wood engravings for Poems of Shelley and encloses two photographs of the collection.
  - Promotional brochure for The Boke of Ilford. Illustrated by Richard Shirley Smith., 2009?; 3 pages; 13.5 x 18 cm (Box 2, Folder 83)
    Inscribed in ink: "I can provide this when I see you. You only now have an unattractive paperback, which was an afterthought." Attached to page 32 of the Richard Shirley Smith annotated checklist.
  - Assorted notes and photocopies, 2009?; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; 10 pages (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - Email correspondence between Richard Shirley Smith and Roger W. Moss, 2009 October 6; Shirley Smith, Richard; 3 pages; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 85)
    Shirley Smith and Moss discuss the wood engravings for Poems of Percy Bysshe Shelly.
  - Email to Richard Shirley Smith, 2009 September 18; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; 2 pages; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 86)
    Moss discusses purchasing the wood engravings for Poems of Percy Bysshe Shelly.
  - Correspondence between Roger W. Moss and Richard Shirley Smith, 2009 December 2; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; 1 page; 29.5 x 21 cm (Box 2, Folder 87)
    Moss discusses the current draft of the bibliography and asks for corrections. Shirley Smith includes his corrections on the same page.
  - Email to Richard Shirley Smith, 2009 December 2; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; 1 page; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 88)
    Moss discusses the draft of the bibliography and asks Shirley Smith to make corrections.
  - Email to Roger W. Moss, 2009 December 13; Shirley Smith, Richard; 2 pages; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 89)
    Shirley Smith discusses the draft of the bibliography and the possibility of contacting the Yale Center for British Art regarding the collection.
  - Letter to Richard Shirley Smith, 2010 January 22; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; 1 page; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 90)
    Moss discusses the draft of the bibliography and his plans to visit Shirley Smith during his upcoming trip to London.
  - Letter to Roger W. Moss, 2010 January?; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 page; 29.5 x 21 cm (Box 3, Folder 91)
    Shirley Smith lists collections of books he has contributed to, suggesting they form a "mini biography" of his work.
  - Email correspondence between Roger W. Moss and Richard Shirley Smith, 2010 January 22; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; 1 page; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 3, Folder 92)
    Moss and Shirley Smith discuss Moss's upcoming visit to London.
  - Email correspondence between Roger W. Moss and Richard Shirley Smith, 2010 January 23; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; 2 pages; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 3, Folder 93)
    Moss and Shirley Smith discuss Libanus Press.
    Electronic mail; Shirley Smith, Richard; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; Libanus Press
  - Email correspondence between Roger W. Moss and Richard Shirley Smith, 2010 January 31; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; 2 pages; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 3, Folder 94)
    Shirley Smith and Moss discuss printing the bibliography through Libanus Press.
    Electronic mail; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; Shirley Smith, Richard; Libanus Press
  - Email correspondence between Richard Shirley Smith and Roger W. Moss, 2010 February 3; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; 2 pages; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 3, Folder 95)
    Shirley Smith and Moss discuss details regarding printing the bibliography.
  - Email correspondence between Roger W. Moss and Richard Shirley Smith, 2010 February 17; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; 1 page; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 3, Folder 96)
    Moss discusses revising the checklist, Libanus Press, and an inventory of Shirley Smith's bookplates and ephemera.
  - Email to Richard Shirley Smith, 2010 February 23; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; 2 pages; 28 x 1.5 cm (Box 3, Folder 97)
    Moss outlines the itinerary for his March visit to London in order to schedule a meeting with Libanus.
  - Letter to Miranda Shirley Smith and Michael Sharkley, 2010 March 18; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; 1 page; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 3, Folder 98)
    Moss discusses his Richard Shirley Smith collection.
    Correspondence; Sharkley, Michael; Shirley Smith, Miranda; Moss, Roger W., 1940-
  - Email correspondence between Roger W. Moss and Richard Shirley Smith, 2010 March 19; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; 1 page; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 3, Folder 99)
    Moss requests Miranda Shirley Smith's mailing address so that he can send her a thank you note.
  - Letter to Roger W. Moss, 2010 March 27; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; 1 page; 29.5 x 21 cm (Box 3, Folder 100)
    Shirley Smith discusses his work for the Limited Editions Club of New York and the contents of a package he will send to Moss.
  - Email to Richard Shirley Smith, 2010 March 30; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; 1 page; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 3, Folder 101)
    Moss discusses the Shelley project and the Limited Editions Club.
    Electronic mail; Shirley Smith, Richard; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; Limited Editions Club
  - Email correspondence between Roger W. Moss and Richard Shirley Smith, 2010; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; 2 pages; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 3, Folder 101b)
    Moss discusses Heritage Press and Limited Editions Club printings of The Poems of Percy Bysshe Shelley.
    Electronic mail; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; Shirley Smith, Richard; Limited Editions Club; Heritage Press (New York, N.Y.)
  - Email correspondence between Roger W. Moss and Richard Shirley Smith, 2010 August 3; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; 3 pages; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 3, Folder 102)
    Moss and Shirley Smith discuss details regarding printing the checklist, including the dust jacket design and internal illustrations.
  - Email correspondence between Michael Mitchell, Roger W. Moss, and Richard Shirley Smith, 2010 August 9; Mitchell, Michael, 1939-; 3 pages; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 3, Folder 103)
    Moss makes corrections to the checklist. Moss, Mitchell, and Shirley Smith also discuss the book's design.
    Electronic mail; Mitchell, Michael, 1939-; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; Shirley Smith, Richard
  - Correspondence between Michael Mitchell, Roger W. Moss, and Richard Shirley Smith, 2010 August 22; Shirley Smith, Richard; 2 pages; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 3, Folder 104)
    Mitchell, Moss, and Shirley Smith discuss the Shirley Smith checklist typesetting proof.
    Correspondence; Mitchell, Michael, 1939-; Shirley Smith, Richard; Moss, Roger W., 1940-
  - Email to Michael Mitchell, 2010 August 22; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; 1 page; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 3, Folder 105)
    Moss discusses revisions to the Shirley Smith checklist typesetting proof and encloses a list of the corrections.
    Electronic mail; Mitchell, Michael, 1939-; Moss, Roger W., 1940-
  - Email correspondence between Michael Mitchell, Roger W. Moss, and Richard Shirley Smith, 2010 October 20; Shirley Smith, Richard; 2 pages; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 3, Folder 106)
    Mitchell, Moss, and Shirley Smith discuss printing and delivery of the books.
    Electronic mail; Mitchell, Michael, 1939-; Shirley Smith, Richard; Moss, Roger W., 1940-
  - Email to Richard Shirley Smith, 2010 October 20; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; 1 page; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 3, Folder 107)
    Moss discusses numbering and signing Moss's checklist as well as distribution for the book.
  - Invoice from Libanus Press, 2010 October 26; Libanus Press; 2 pages; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 3, Folder 108)
    Invoice for "The Moss Collection" book production.
    Invoice; Libanus Press
  - Email to Roger W. Moss, 2010 October 26; Mitchell, Michael, 1939-; 1 page; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 3, Folder 109)
    Mitchell discusses the invoice from Libanus.
  - Email correspondence between Michael Mitchell and Roger W. Moss, 2010 October 26; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; 2 pages; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 3, Folder 110)
    Mitchell and Moss discuss payment for printing Moss's checklist. Moss encloses photocopies of two final proofs of the cover.
  - Email correspondence between Michael Mitchell and Roger W. Moss, 2010 October 26; Mitchell, Michael, 1939-; 2 pages; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 3, Folder 111)
    Mitchell and Moss discuss distribution for Moss's checklist.
    Electronic mail; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; Mitchell, Michael, 1939-
  - Correspondence between Michael Mitchell, Roger W. Moss, and Richard Shirley Smith, 2010 October 26; Shirley Smith, Richard; 2 pages; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 3, Folder 112)
    Moss and Shirley Smith discuss revisions to the checklist and distribution of the book.
    Electronic mail; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; Mitchell, Michael, 1939-; Shirley Smith, Richard
  - Email to Roger W. Moss, 2010 October 27; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; 1 page; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 3, Folder 113)
    Mitchell thanks Moss for his payment.
  - Email correspondence between Roger W. Moss and Richard Shirley Smith, 2010 November 4; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; 2 pages; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 3, Folder 113b)
    Moss discusses distributing the checklist copies.
  - Letter to Richard Shirley Smith, 2010 December 16; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 page; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 3, Folder 114)
    Leder thanks Shirley Smith for donating a copy of Moss's checklist to the Old Speech Room Gallery.
    Correspondence; Leder, Carolyn; Shirley Smith, Richard; Harrow School. Old Speech Room Gallery
  - Copy of letter to Richard Shirley Smith, 2010 December 22; Burnett, David, 1937-; 1 page; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 3, Folder 115)
    Burnett thanks Shirley Smith for Moss's checklist and compliments his work.
    Correspondence; Shirley Smith, Richard; Burnett, David, 1937-
  - Email correspondence between Anthony Baker and Roger W. Moss, 2010 December 24; Baker, Anthony Baden; 1 page; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 3, Folder 116)
    Two copies. Baker and Moss discuss Moss's checklist and the memorial folds for Baker's parents, which use Shirley Smith's woodcuts.
    Electronic mail; Baker, Anthony Baden; Moss, Roger W., 1940-
  - Email to Roger W. Moss, 2010 December 24; Baker, Anthony Baden; 2 pages; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 3, Folder 117)
    Baker discusses his parents' memorial engravings made by Richard Shirley Smith and corrects the Moss checklist's entry for Buzz Buzz, stating that all two hundred copies are signed by the author and the artist.
  - Email correspondence between Roger W. Moss and Richard Shirley Smith, 2011 January 3; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 page; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 3, Folder 118)
    Moss and Shirley Smith discuss the recent snowstorms in Europe.
  - Letter to Richard Shirley Smith, 2011 January 19; Fletcher, Chris, 1967-; 1 page; 29.5 x 21 cm (Box 3, Folder 119)
    Fletcher thanks Shirley Smith for the book and asks for information about his upcoming London show.
    Correspondence; Shirley Smith, Richard; Fletcher, Chris, 1967-; Shirley Smith, Richard -- Exhibitions
  - Letter to Roger W. Moss, 2011 January 26; Askam, Mark; 1 page; 29.5 x 21 cm (Box 3, Folder 120)
    Askam discusses and encloses a bibliography of Richard Shirley Smith bookplates. Moss's checklist and an email correspondence between Mark Askam, Anthony Baker, Roger W. Moss, and Richard Shirley Smith are also enclosed.
    Correspondence; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; Askam, Mark
  - Letter to Richard Shirley Smith, 2011 February 1; Blundell, Joe Whitlock; 1 page; 29.5 x 21 cm (Box 3, Folder 121)
    Blundell discusses Moss's checklist and Shirley Smith's upcoming London show.
    Correspondence; Blundell, Joe Whitlock; Shirley Smith, Richard; Shirley Smith, Richard -- Exhibitions
  - Letter to Richard Shirley Smith, 2011 February 2; Thomas, Sarah (Sarah E.); 1 page; 29.5 x 21 cm (Box 3, Folder 122)
    Thomas thanks Shirley Smith for his gift of Roger Moss's checklist.
    Correspondence; Thomas, Sarah (Sarah E.); Shirley Smith, Richard
  - Letter to Roger and Gail Moss, 2011 February 5; Shirley Smith, Richard; 1 page; 15 x 21 cm (Box 3, Folder 122a)
    Shirley Smith thanks Moss for his collection and catalogue and mentions Stephen Calloway at the Victoria and Albert Museum.
    Correspondence; Shirley Smith, Richard; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; Victoria and Albert Museum; Calloway, Stephen
  - Email to Richard Shirley Smith, 2011 February 17; Moss, Roger W., 1940-; 1 page; 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 3, Folder 123)
    Moss discusses acknowledgement letters for the Richard Shirley Smith checklist.
  - Letter to Richard Shirley Smith, 2011?; Bain, Iain; 1 page; 29.5 x 21 cm (Box 3, Folder 124)
    Bain thanks Shirley Smith for the Moss collection catalogue.
    Correspondence; Shirley Smith, Richard; Bain, Iain
  - Letter to Richard Shirley Smith, 2011 January 14; Griffiths, Antony; 1 page; 29.5 x 21 cm (Box 3, Folder 125)
    Griffiths thanks Shirley Smith for the Moss Collection catalogue.
    Correspondence; Shirley Smith, Richard; Griffiths, Antony